var events = [
{year:1947, question:'Pakistan?', yAnswer: 'Yes', nAnswer: 'No', yes:[[1947,null]], no:[[null,1947]]},
{year:1905, question:'Is the "United Kingdom of Sweden and Norway" a single nation?', yAnswer:"Yes", nAnswer:"No", yes:[[1814,1905]], no:[[null,1814],[1905,null]]}, 
{year:1830, question:'Do either of Venezuela or Ecuador exist as independent states?', yAnswer:"Yes", nAnswer:"No", yes:[[1830,null]], no:[[null,1830]]},
{year:1806, question:'Does The Holy Roman Empire exist?', yAnswer: 'Yes', nAnswer: 'No', yes:[[899,1806]], no:[[null,899], [1806, null]]},
{year:1776, question:'Does the United States of America exist?', yAnswer: 'Yes', nAnswer: 'No', yes:[[1776,null]], no:[[null,1776]]},
{year:1811, question:'Paraguay?', yAnswer:"Yes", nAnswer:"No", yes:[[1811,null]], no:[[null,1811]]},
{year:1821, question: "Is Florida a part of ...?", yAnswer: 'Spain', nAnswer: 'USA', yes:[[null,1821]], no:[[1821,null]]},
{year:1846, question: "Is Texas a part of the USA?", yAnswer: 'Yes', nAnswer: 'No', yes:[[1846,null]], no:[[null,1846]]},
{year:1836, question: "Is Texas a part of Mexico?", yAnswer: 'Yes', nAnswer: 'No', yes:[[1718,1836]], no:[[null,1718],[1836, null]]},
{year:1858, question:'Does Russia border the Sea of Japan?', yAnswer:"Yes", nAnswer:"No", yes:[[1858,null]], no:[[null,1858]]}, 
{year:1868, question: 'Do any of these exist? <ul><li>Independent Canada</li><li>Alaska as part of the US</li><li>Tokyo</li></ul>', yAnswer: 'Yes', nAnswer: 'No', yes:[[1868,null]], no:[[null,1867]]}, 
{year:1922, question: 'Does the Soviet Union Exist?', yAnswer: 'Yes', nAnswer: 'No', yes:[[1922,1991]], no:[[null, 1922], [1991,null]]}, 
{year:1924, question:'Leningrad?', yAnswer:"Yes", nAnswer:"No", yes:[[1924,1991]], no:[[null,1924],[1991,null]]},
{year:1912, question:'Albania?', yAnswer:"Yes", nAnswer:"No", yes:[[1912,null]], no:[[null,1912]]},
{year:1910, question:'South Africa?', yAnswer:"Yes", nAnswer:"No", yes:[[1910,null]], no:[[null,1910]]},
{year:1918, question:'Is there a single Austria-Hungary nation?', yAnswer:"Yes", nAnswer:"No", yes:[[1867,1918]], no:[[null,1867],[1918,null]]}, 
{year:1922, question:'Does the Ottoman Empire exist?', yAnswer:"Yes", nAnswer:"No", yes:[[1299,1922]], no:[[null,1299],[1923,null]]},
{year:1932, question:'Saudi Arabia?' , yAnswer: 'Yes', nAnswer: 'No', yes:[[1932,null]], no:[[null,1932]]},
{year:1928, question: 'Istanbul or Constantinople?', yAnswer: 'Constantinople', nAnswer: 'Istanbul', yes:[[null,1928]], no:[[1928, null]]}, 
{year:1930, question:'Is Jan Mayen part of the kingdom of Norway?', yAnswer: 'Yes', nAnswer: 'Not yet', yes:[[1930,null]], no:[[null,1930]]},
{year:1935, question:'Persia or Iran?', yAnswer:"Iran", nAnswer:"Persia", yes:[[1935,null]], no:[[null,1934]]},
{year:1945, question:'Do either North Korea or Vietnam exist?' , yAnswer: 'Yes', nAnswer: 'No', yes:[[1945,null]], no:[[null,1945]]},
{year:1980, question:'The Sinai is mostly part of what nation?', yAnswer:"Egypt", nAnswer:"Israel", yes:[[null,1967],[1982,null]], no:[[1967,1981]]},
{year:1960, question:'Budapest is a single city or are Buda and Pest separate cities?', yAnswer:"Buda and Pest", nAnswer:"Budapest", yes:[[1274,1873]], no:[[1873,null]]}, 
{year:1953, question:'Cambodia?', yAnswer:"Yes", nAnswer:"No", yes:[[1953,null]], no:[[null,1953]]},
{year:1948, question:'Israel?', yAnswer:"Yes", nAnswer:"No", yes:[[1948,null]], no:[[null,1948]]},
{year:1952, question:'Is Eritrea part of Ethiopia?', yAnswer:"Yes", nAnswer:"No", yes:[[1952,1993]], no:[[null,1952],[1993,null]]},
{year:1958, question:'United Arab Republic?', yAnswer:"Yes", nAnswer:"No", yes:[[1958,1961]], no:[[null,1958],[1961,null]]},
{year:1960, question:'Is most of West Africa a giant French blob?', yAnswer: 'Yes', nAnswer: 'No', yes:[[1895,1960]], no:[[null,1895],[1960,null]]},
{year:1971, question:'Zaire?', yAnswer:"Yes", nAnswer:"No",  yes:[[1971,1997]], no:[[null,1971],[1997,null]]},
{year:1965, question:'Is the nation south of Lake Victoria called Tanzania?', yAnswer:"Yes", nAnswer:"No", yes:[[1965,null]], no:[[null,1964]]},
{year:1967, question:'Yemen?', yAnswer:"Yes", nAnswer:"No",  yes:[[1967,null]], no:[[null,1967]]},
{year:1972, question:'Bangladesh?', yAnswer:"Yes", nAnswer:"No", yes:[[1972,null]], no:[[null,1972]]},
{year:1976, question:'How many Vietnams are there?', yAnswer:"One", nAnswer:"Two", yes:[[1948,1955],[1976,null]], no:[[1955,1976]]},
{year:1992, question:'Czechoslovakia?', yAnswer:"Yes", nAnswer:"No",  yes:[[1919,1992]], no:[[null,1918],[1992,null]]},
{year:1989, question:'Myanmar or Burma?', yAnswer:"Myanmar", nAnswer:"Burma", yes:[[1989,null]], no:[[null,1989]]},
{year:1980, question:'Rhodesia?', yAnswer:"Yes", nAnswer:"No", yes:[[1895,1980]], no:[[null,1895],[1980,null]]},
{year:1984, question:'Burkina Faso?', yAnswer:"Yes", nAnswer:"No", yes:[[1984,null]], no:[[null,1984]]},
{year:1990, question:'How many Germanys are there?', yAnswer: 'One', nAnswer: 'Two', yes:[[1871,1945],[1990,null]], no:[[1946,1990]]},
{year:1991, question: 'Does the Soviet Union Exist?', yAnswer: 'Yes', nAnswer: 'No', yes:[[1922,1991]], no:[[null, 1922], [1991,null]]}, 
{year:2006, question:'Is Montenegro a separate independent nation?', yAnswer:"Yes", nAnswer:"No", yes:[[null,1918],[2006,null]], no:[[1918,2006]]},
{year:1993, question:'Is Eritrea an idependent nation?', yAnswer:"Yes", nAnswer:"No", yes:[[1993,null]], no:[[null,1993]]},
{year:2002, question:'Is East Timor a separate independent nation?', yAnswer:"Yes", nAnswer:"No", yes:[[2002,null]], no:[[null,2002]]},
{year:2014, question:'Is Crimea either disputed or part of Russia?', yAnswer:"Yes", nAnswer:"No", yes:[[2014,null]], no:[[null,2014]]},
{year:2007, question:'Is South Sudan a separate independent nation?', yAnswer:"Yes", nAnswer:"No", yes:[[2007,null]], no:[[null,2007]]},
{year:2016, question:'Czechia?', yAnswer:"Yes", nAnswer:"No", yes:[[2016,null]], no:[[null,null]]},

];
